Stephen J. Gould papers M1437
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - Subseries: Incoming Letters, 1997-2000
    - Sa - Si (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - Sl - Sw (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - T (Box 106, Folder 14)
    - V (Box 106, Folder 15)
    - Watanabe, Masataka (Box 106, Folder 16)
    - W (Box 106, Folder 17)
    - Young, Ned (Box 106, Folder 18)
    - Y - Z (Box 106, Folder 19)
    - Unknown (Box 106, Folder 20)
  - Subseries: Incoming Letters, 2002
    - A - B (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - D - G (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - H - J (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - K - M (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - M (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - N - R (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Stone, Jonathon Richard (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - S - W (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Unknown (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: Outgoing Letters, 1974-2000
    - 1974-1979; includes letter to W. W. Howells (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - January 1980; includes letters to John Beaman, Howard Margolis, Ashley Montagu, Steven Selden, Frank Sulloway (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - February 1980; includes letter to Luis W. Alvarez (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - March 1980; includes letter to Malcolm J. Kottler (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - April 1980 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - May 1980; includes letter to Roy A. Gallant (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - June 1980; includes letters to R. Buckminster Fuller, Jeffrey S. Levinton, Thomas J. M. Schopf (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - July 1980; includes letters to Ed Barber, Henry Louis Gates, Jr., Antoni Hoffman, Michael E. Levin, Norman D. Newell, G. Ledyard Stebbins (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - August 1980; includes letters to H. R. Booher, Henry Louis Gates, Jr., Sir Peter Medawar, Ashley Montagu, George Gaylord Simpson, John Terrell (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - September 1980; includes letter to Beverly Halstead (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - October 1980; includes letters to Ashley Montagu, Charles R. Pellegrino (Box 108, Folder 11)
    - November 1980; includes letters to Jon Marks, Alan Ternes (Box 108, Folder 12)
    - December 1980; includes letters to Norman Newell, George Gaylord Simpson (Box 108, Folder 13)
    - January 1981; includes letters to John Maddox, David M. Raup, G. Ledyard Stebbins, Sewall Wright (Box 108, Folder 14)
    - February 1981; includes letters to Niles Eldredge, Douglas J. Futuyama, A. L. A. Johnson, G. Ledyard Stebbins, Alan Ternes (Box 108, Folder 15)
    - March 1981; includes letters to Paul R. Ehrlich, Donald O. Walter, Sewall Wright (Box 108, Folder 16)
    - April 1981; includes letters to Allen L. Hammond, Norman D. Newell, Thomas J. M. Schopf, Alan Ternes (Box 108, Folder 17)
    - May 1981; includes letter to Ashley Montagu (Box 108, Folder 18)
    - June 1981 (Box 108, Folder 19)
    - July 1981; includes letter to Leon Jaroff (Box 108, Folder 20)
    - August 1981; includes letter to B. F. Skinner (Box 108, Folder 21)
    - September 1981; includes letters to Jeremy Cherfas, Peter Costello, D. A. Hooijer (Box 108, Folder 22)
    - October 1981; includes letters to Alan Ternes, Elisabeth S. Vrba (Box 108, Folder 23)
    - November 1981; includes letters to John Mansfield, John Maynard Smith, G. Ledyard Stebbins (Box 108, Folder 24)
    - December 1981; includes letter to Ralph Nader (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - January 1982; includes letters to Fuzz Crompton, Ernst Mayr, Monty Slatkin (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - February 1982; includes letter to Roy J. Britten (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - March 1982; includes letter to Alan Ternes (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - April 1982; includes letter to Sir Andrew Huxley (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - May 1982; includes letter to Roger Angell (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - June 1982; includes letter to Simon Tillier (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - July 1982; includes letters to Gabriel A. Dover, R. E. Leakey (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - August 1982; includes letter to Alan Ternes (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - September 1982; includes letters to Ernst Mayr, Linus Pauling (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - October 1982 (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - November 1982; includes letter to Linus Pauling (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - December 1982; includes letters to R. K. Bambach, Carl Sagan (Box 109, Folder 13)
    - January 1983; includes letters to Kevin Padian, Carl Sagan, Thomas J. M. Schopf, Robert Silvers, John Maynard Smith, Alan Ternes, Simon Tillier (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - February 1983; includes letters to Isaac Asimov, Robert Silvers, Alan Ternes, Simon Tillier (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - March 1983 (Box 109, Folder 16)
    - April 1983; includes letters to Robert Silvers, G. A. Dover (Box 109, Folder 17)
    - May 1983; includes letters to Paul A. Samuelson, Alan Ternes (Box 109, Folder 18)
    - June 1983; includes letters to Niles Eldredge, David Jablonski, Frank H. T. Rhodes, Thomas J. M. Schopf, Alan Ternes (Box 109, Folder 19)
    - July 1983 (Box 109, Folder 20)
    - August 1983; includes letters to Joe DiMaggio, Gabriel Dover, Alan Ternes (Box 109, Folder 21)
    - September 1983; includes letters to Henry Louis Gates, Jr., Allen Hammond, Richard Milner, Alan Ternes (Box 109, Folder 22)
    - October 1983; includes letters to Alan Ternes, Elisabeth Vrba (Box 109, Folder 23)
    - November 1983; includes letters to G. A. Dover, David Jablonski, Carl Sagan, T. J. M. Schopf, Alan Ternes (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - December 1983; includes letters to Henry Louis Gates, Jr., David G. King (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - January 1984; includes letters to Jim McCarthy, J. J. Sepkoski (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - February 1984; includes letters to Anne S. Fernald, Martin Gardner, Ernst Mayr, Carl Sagan (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - March 1984; includes letter to Ashley Montagu (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - April 1984; includes letters to Leon Eisenberg, J. J. Sepkoski (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - May 1984; includes letters to Noam Chomsky, Norman L. Gilinsky, Sir Peter Medawar, Carl Sagan, J. J. Sepkoski, Frank H. Talbot, Alan Ternes (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - June 1984; includes letters to Derek Bok, Niles Eldredge, Odlie Jacob, Leo F. Laporte, Ashley Montagu, F. H. T. Rhodes, John Maynard Smith, Alan Ternes (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - July 1984; includes letters to Richard Dawkins, Liam Hudson, Norman L. Gilinsky, Jim Lovelock, R. K. Merton, J. J. Sepkoski, Alan Ternes (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - August 1984 (Box 110, Folder 10)
    - September 1984; includes letters to Alan Ternes, Elisabeth S. Vrba (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - October 1984; includes letter to Elisabeth S. Vrba (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - November 1984; includes letters to Carl Sagan, J. J. Sepkoski, Alan Ternes, Adrienne Zihlman (Box 110, Folder 13)
    - December 1984; includes letters to Robert K. Merton, David M. Raup, J. William Schopf, J. J. Sepkoski, Gene Shalit, Alan Ternes (Box 110, Folder 14)
    - January 1985; includes letters to Ed Barber, Joe DiMaggio, Norman L. Gilinsky, Charles Sibley (Box 110, Folder 15)
    - February 1985; includes letters to Mary S. Calderone, Joel E. Cohen, Thomas M. Cronin, Carl Sagan, Charles G. Sibley, Alan Ternes (Box 110, Folder 16)
    - March 1985; includes letter to Alan Ternes (Box 110, Folder 17)
    - April 1985; includes letter to J. J. Sepkoski, Charles G. Sibley, Elisabeth S. Vrba, Allan C. Wilson (Box 110, Folder 18)
    - May 1985; includes letters to C. D. Michener, Alan Ternes, D. S. Woodruff (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - June 1985; includes letters to Ed Barber, Phil Donohue, Roger Lewin (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - July 1985; includes letters to Linnda R. Caporael, Martin Gardner, Sharon Kingsland, Ashley Montagu, Naomi Rand, David Raup, M. J. S. Rudwick, Charles C. Sibley (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - August 1985 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - September 1985; includes letters to Karen Antman, Richard Dawkins, Gabriel Dover, Niles Eldredge, Elizabeth Pachoda, David M. Raup, Carl Sagan and Ann Druyan, J. J. Sepkoski (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - October 1985; includes letters to Jill Krementz and Kurt Vonnegut, Will Provine (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - November 1985; includes letters to Mildred Susman, Alan Ternes (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - December 1985; includes letters to Ed Barber, Linnda R. Caporael, Donald R. Prothero, Gary D. Schnell, Gene Shalit (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - January 1986; includes letters to Peter R. Crane, Paul R. Ehrlich, Roger Lewin, Arthur Rosenthal, Michael Spence (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - February 1986; includes letters to David Jablonski, John L. Locke, Jennifer Rogers, Gary D. Schnell, Charles Sibley, Alan Ternes (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - March 1986; includes letters to Tony Arnold, Kent E. Holsinger, Ernst Mayr, Richard M. Mitterer, Norman D. Newell (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - April 1986; includes letters to Ed Purcell (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - May 1986; includes letters to March H. Anders, Carl Sagan, Michael A. Spence (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - June 1986; includes letters to Mark H. Anders, Bettyann Kevles, Alan Ternes (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - July 1986 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - August 1986; includes letters to Carl Sagan, Alan Ternes (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - September 1986; includes letters to Linnda R. Caporael, Lynn Margulis, Richard D. Maxson, Lynn J. Rothschild, J. William Schopf, Camille Smith, David Whitford (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - October 1986; includes letters to C. S. Grobbelaar, Migs Grove, Alan Ternes (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - November 1986; includes letters to Will Provine (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - December 1986; includes letters to Preston Cloud, Jack Novik, Ed Purcell, David M. Raup, Dieter Schierenberg, Alan Ternes (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - January 1987; includes letters to Carl Sagan, Alan Ternes (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - February 1987; includes letters to Derek V. Ager, Alan Ternes, David S. Woodruff (Box 111, Folder 22)
    - March 1987; includes letters to Alan D. Hecht, Carl Sagan (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - April 1987; includes letters to James J. McCarthy, Everett C. Olson, Bill Schopf, Alan Ternes (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - May 1987 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - June 1987; includes letters to Ed Barber, Gayle Munchow, Timothy W. Sipe, Alan Ternes (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - July 1987 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - August 1987; includes letters to Carl N. Degler, John M. Saul (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - September 1987; includes letters to Jeffrey Boak, David G. Frodin, Marion J. Levy, Jr., Ashley Montagu, Ed Purcell, Kristine H. Templeman (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - October 1987; includes letters to William B. Provine, Alan Ternes (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - November 1987; includes letters to Julia Child, Ernst Mayr, Ed Purcell, Phil W. Signor, Steve Stanley, Jay Topkins (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - December 1987; includes letter to Jack Sepkoski (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - January 1988; includes letters to Marcus W. Feldman, Max Hecht, Ernst Mayr, David M. Raup, Alan Ternes (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - February 1988; includes lettesr to Allan O. Kelly, Alan Ternes (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - March 1988; includes letter to Jack Selzer (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - April 1988 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - May 1988; includes letters to Douglas J. Futuyama, Robert McC. Adams, Alan Ternes (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - June 1988; includes letter to Robert Silvers (Box 112, Folder 16)
    - August 1988; includes letters to Marianne Collins, Alan Ternes, Masataka Watanabe (Box 112, Folder 17)
    - September 1988 (Box 112, Folder 18)
    - October 1988; includes letters to Carl Sagan, Alan Ternes (Box 112, Folder 19)
    - November 1988; includes letters to Alan O. Kelly, Carl Sagan, Alan Ternes (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - December 1988; includes letters to J. David Baldwin, Paul Ehrlich (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - January 1989; includes letters to Susan E. Abrams, Anthony Hallam (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - February 1989; includes letters to Lawrence Hurst, David Jablonski, Robert K. Merton, Curtis Runnels (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - March 1989; includes letters to Paula Apsell, Carl Sagan (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - April 1989; includes letters to George D. Langdon, Michael Ruse, Carl Sagan (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - May 1989; includes letters to John Cirace (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - June 1989; includes letters to Pere Alberch, Roger Angell, R. J. Berry, Takashi Okamoto (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - July 1989; includes letters to Howard Boyer, John Brockman, Jimmy Carter, Carl Djerassi, Gabriel Dover, Alan Fern, Bruce L. Firstman, Christine Gilbert, Harry Kemelman, Motoo Kimura, John Maynard Smith, Robert K. Merton, Ravi Mirchandani, Charles Sibley, Robert Silvers, Alan Ternes (Box 113, Folder 9)
    - August 1989 (Box 113, Folder 10)
    - September 1989; includes letters to Stefan Bengtson, John Brockman, Leon Eisenberg, Christine Gilbert, Norman L. Gilinsky, Akio Niizuman, Jack Selzer (Box 113, Folder 11)
    - October 1989; includes letters to Bob Katz (Box 113, Folder 12)
    - November 1989; includes letters to Neil Belton, Geoffrey Palmer, Robert Silvers (Box 113, Folder 13)
    - December 1989; includes letters to Neil Belton, Jimmy Carter, John Eccles, Eugenie C. Scott (Box 113, Folder 14)
    - January 1990; includes letters to Gene H. Albrecht, Carl Sagan, Gene Schalet (Box 113, Folder 15)
    - February 1990; includes letters to Pere Alberch, Larry Grinell, Michael Spence, Alan Ternes (Box 113, Folder 16)
    - March 1990; includes letters to Pippa Skotnes (Box 113, Folder 17)
    - April 1990; includes letters to Marcel Blanc, A. Michael Spence, Peter R. Sheldon, Alan [Ternes] (Box 113, Folder 18)
    - May 1990; includes letters to Milton Rogovin, Pippa Skotnes, Michael Spence (Box 113, Folder 19)
    - June 1990; includes letters to Ed Barber, Jean-Marc Levy-Leblond, Ravi Mirchandani, Alan Ternes (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - July 1990; includes letters to Susan E. Abrams, Ed Barber, Dick Johnson, Robert J. Silvers (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - August 1990; includes letters to Marcel Blanc, Eugenie C. Scott, Robert Silvers, Pippa Skotnes (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - September 1990; includes letters to Alan Ternes (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - October 1990; includes letters to Alan Dershowitz, Carl Djerassi, Alan Fern, Bob Gale, Ernst [Mayr], Alan [Ternes], Sheila Weiner (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - November 1990; includes letters to Neil Belton, Leigh Van Valen, George Will (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - December 1990; includes letters to Howard E. Boyer, Jr., Peter Dodson, Daniel E. Koshland, Peter N. Nevraumont (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - January 1991; includes letters to Pere Alberch, Carl Djerassi, Norman Dorsen, Alan Fern, Milton Rogovin, Oliver Sacks, Alan [Ternes], Allan C. Wilson (Box 114, Folder 8)
    - February 1991; includes letters to Ed Purcell, Rhonda Roland Shearer (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - March 1991; includes letters to Ed Barber, Marcel Bronc, Ken Burns, Carl Djerassi, Anthony Hallam, Ravi Marchandani, Rhonda Roland Shearer (Box 114, Folder 10)
    - April 1991; includes letters to Milton Rogovin, Alan Ternes (Box 114, Folder 11)
    - May 1991; includes letter to Geerat J. Vermeij (Box 114, Folder 12)
    - June 1991; includes letters to Stefan Bengtson, Alan Ternes (Box 114, Folder 13)
    - July 1991; includes letters to Jimmy Carter, David R. Lees (Box 114, Folder 14)
    - August 1991; includes letters to Michael Kruger, Judith Masters, Alan Ternes, J. F. Thackeray (Box 114, Folder 15)
    - September 1991; includes letters to Norman D. Newell, Milton Rogovin (Box 114, Folder 16)
    - October 1991; includes letter to Alan Ternes (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - November 1991; includes letters to Marcel Blanc, Jack P. Hailman, Pippa Skotnes (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - December 1991; includes letters to Alan Fern, Milton Rogovin (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - January 1992; includes letters to Robert K. Merton, Carl Sagan and Ann Druyan (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - February 1992; includes letters to Edwin Barber, Neil Belton, Jurgen Brosius, Jack G. Hawkes (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - March 1992; includes letters to Marcel Blanc, Laurie Block, Roger Lass, Judith Masters, Michael Ruse, George Scribner, Betty Smocovitis, Alan Ternes (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - April 1992; includes letters to Ed Barber, Pino Donghi, Robert E. Machol, Robert K. Merton, C. A. Tripp (Box 115, Folder 7)
    - May 1992 (Box 115, Folder 8)
    - June 1992; includes letters to Marcel Blanc, Bill Clinton, Gerta Keller, Robert K. Merton (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - July 1992; includes letter to Alan Ternes (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - August 1992; includes letters to Jared M. Diamond, Jim Mairs, Robert Silvers (Box 115, Folder 11)
    - September 1992; includes letters to Ed Barber, Jurgen Brosius, Elisabeth Lloyd (Box 115, Folder 12)
    - October 1992; includes letter to Anthony Hallam (Box 115, Folder 13)
    - November 1992; includes letters to Laurie Block, Milton Rogovin (Box 115, Folder 14)
    - December 1992; includes letters to Marcel Blanc, Jean-Marc Levy-Leblond (Box 115, Folder 15)
    - January 1993 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - February 1993; includes letters to Valerie Neal, Martin J. S. Rudwick, Alan Ternes (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - March 1993; includes letter to Neil Belton, Alan Ternes (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - April 1993; includes letters to Alan Ternes, Harrison L. Townes (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - May 1993; includes letters to Neil Belton, Alan Ternes (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - June 1993; includes letters to Henry Gee, Claudia Rex (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - July 1993; includes letters to Roger Chartier, Evan R. Ferguson, Robert E. Machol, Ravi Mirchandani (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - August 1993; includes letters to Juliet Clutton-Brock, Joseph A. Reif, Oliver Sacks, Charles Sibley (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - September 1993; includes letters to Henry Gee, Alan Ternes (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - October 1993; includes letters to Joan Simpson Burns, Henry Gee, Ravi Mirchandani (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - November 1993; includes letter to Joan Simpson Burns (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - December 1993; includes letters to Oliver Sacks, Stephen A. Schellenberg (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - January 1994; includes letters to Arnold I. Miller, Alan Ternes (Box 116, Folder 13)
    - February 1994; includes letters to Neil Belton, Ellen Futter, A. Richard Palmer, Milton and Anne Rogovin, Alan Ternes (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - March 1994 (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - April 1994; includes letters to William B. Goodman and Joan Simpson Burns, Ed O. Wilson (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - May 1994; includes letter to Jean-Claude Moreno (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - June 1994; includes letter to Michelle Press (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - July 1994; includes letters to Arthur C. Clarke, Alice Gordon, Ravi Mirchandani, Michelle Press (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - August 1994; includes letters to Arthur C. Clarke, Lorraine Glennon, Ernst Mayr (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - September 1994; includes letters to Ken Burns and Lynn Novick, Steve Dent, Rick Hieb, Barry O. Jones, Arthur G. Sylvester (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - October 1994; includes letters to Alan M. Dershowitz, Michelle Press (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - November 1994; includes letters to Hillary Clinton, Laurie Godfrey, Al Gore, Pippa Skotnes (Box 117, Folder 10)
    - December 1994 (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - January 1995 (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - February 1995; includes letter to Robert R. Sokal (Box 117, Folder 13)
    - March 1995; includes letter to Marcel Blanc (Box 117, Folder 14)
    - April 1995 (Box 117, Folder 15)
    - May 1995 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - June 1995 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - July 1995; includes letter to Ed Barber (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - August 1995 (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - September 1995; includes letter to E. O. Wilson (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - October 1995 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - November 1995; includes letters to Marcel Blanc, Y. Hirono, F. Matsumoto and M. Isibashi (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - December 1995 (Box 118, Folder 8)
    - January 1996 (Box 118, Folder 9)
    - February 1996; includes letter to Leslie Meredith (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - March 1996 (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - April 1996; includes letter to David Jablonski (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - May 1996; includes letter to Peter G. Brown (Box 118, Folder 13)
    - June 1996; includes letters to Henry Gee and Milton Rogovin (Box 118, Folder 14)
    - July 1996; includes letter to M. Watanabe (Box 118, Folder 15)
    - August 1996 (Box 118, Folder 16)
    - September 1996 (Box 118, Folder 17)
    - October 1996; includes letter to Al Gore (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - November 1996 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - December 1996 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - January 1997 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - February 1997; includes letter to Marcel Blanc (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - March 1997; includes letter to Andrew Stewart (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - April 1997; includes letters to Jane Childress, Bob Hensley, Bob Silvers (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - May 1997 (Box 119, Folder 8)
    - June 1997 (Box 119, Folder 9)
    - July 1997; includes letter to Al Lazen, Don Kennedy and colleagues (Box 119, Folder 10)
    - September 1997 (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - October 1997 (Box 119, Folder 12)
    - November 1997 (Box 119, Folder 13)
    - December 1997; includes letter to Emma Carter (Box 119, Folder 14)
    - January 1998 (Box 119, Folder 15)
    - February 1998 (Box 119, Folder 16)
    - March 1998 (Box 119, Folder 17)
    - April 1998; includes letter to Mikhail Gorbachev (Box 119, Folder 18)
    - May 1998 (Box 119, Folder 19)
    - June 1998 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - July 1998 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - August 1998 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - September 1998 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - October 1998; includes letter to Phillip V. Tobias (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - November 1998 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - December 1998; includes letter to David Juncos (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - January 1999; includes letters to David Johnson, Martin Kemp, Ralph W. Lewis (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - February 1999; includes letters to Bill Gates, Dave Peck (Box 120, Folder 9)
    - March 1999; includes letter to Steve Petranek (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - April 1999; includes letter to Alan M. Dershowitz (Box 120, Folder 11)
    - May 1999 (Box 120, Folder 12)
    - June 1999 (Box 120, Folder 13)
    - July 1999 (Box 120, Folder 14)
    - August 1999 (Box 120, Folder 15)
    - September 1999; includes letter to Michael Shermer (Box 120, Folder 16)
    - October 1999; includes letters to Patty Gift, Jean-Marc Levy-Leblond (Box 120, Folder 17)
    - November 1999 (Box 120, Folder 18)
    - December 1999 (Box 120, Folder 19)
    - January 2000 (Box 120, Folder 20)
    - February 2000 (Box 120, Folder 21)
    - March 2000 (Box 120, Folder 22)
    - April 2000 (Box 120, Folder 23)
    - May 2000 (Half-box 121, Folder 1)
    - June 2000 (Half-box 121, Folder 2)
    - August 2000 (Half-box 121, Folder 3)
    - September 2000 (Half-box 121, Folder 4)
    - October 2000 (Half-box 121, Folder 5)
    - November 2000 (Half-box 121, Folder 6)
    - December 2000 (Half-box 121, Folder 7)
    - undated (Half-box 121, Folder 8)
  - Subseries: Letters Removed from Gould's Book Collection
    - Letter to Gould from Marguerite S. Robinson, daughter of Philip VanDoren Stern, January 1, 1990. Laid in Gould’s copy of: The greatest gift: a Christmas tale, by Philip Van Doren Stern. (Half-box 121, Folder 9)
    - Letter to Dr. Hooker from Charles Murchison. Laid in Gould’s copy of: Palæontological memoirs and notes of the late Hugh Falconer. With a biographical sketch of the author. Comp. and ed. by Charles Murchison. (Half-box 121, Folder 10)
    - Letter. Laid in Gould’s copy of: The life and letters of Charles Darwin: including an autobiographical chapter. Edited by his son, Francis Darwin. (Half-box 121, Folder 11)
    - Letter to Mr. Long from Mr. Donald A. Gibson [no date – probably late 1955 or early 1967]. Laid in Gould’s copy of: The headship of Christ and the rights of the Christian people, by Hugh Miller. (Half-box 121, Folder 12)